We have talked about individual process models but we haven't yet talked
我们已经讲了单个过程模型 但是我们还没有讲到
about how to maintain some beliefs about which behavior the driver intends to perform.
如何维护一些预期 这些预期包含了驾驶者接下来的行为倾向
This is the role of multimodal estimation algorithms.
这正是多模估量算法要做的事情
A simple approach to multimodal estimation is called
有一种简单的多模估量算法
autonomous multiple model estimation or AMM.
称为 AMM
While describing AMM, I will use
在描述 AMM 时 我将使用一些符号
the same notation that is used in a paper which I will link to later.
这些符号与稍后我将提及的一篇论文中所使用的相同
The variable M represents the number of process models or
变量 M 代表过程模型数或者行为数
behaviors and each variable mu represents the probability of behavior.
每一个 mu 变量都表示某种行为的几率大小
To understand how these probabilities are computed,
要理解这些几率是如何计算得出的
let's go back to our T intersection example.
让我们回顾一下那个 T 型路口的例子
Let's say we have two process models here.
假设我们在这里有两个过程模型
One to go straight and one to turn right and they both have Gaussian uncertainty.
直行和右转 它们均具有高斯不确定性
Let's say that we observe this state for the vehicle at time k minus one and we observe
假设我们先在时间点 k-1 上观察车辆状态
this state for the vehicle at time k. In order to
然后我们再在时间点 k 上观察
compute the new probabilities for the behaviors based on the new observation,
为了基于新的观察值来计算新的行为几率
we will run our two process models for
我们会从时间点 k-1 时候的状态出发
one step starting from the state at time k minus one.
来运行我们的两个过程模型
When we do this,
当我们这么做的时候
we get these two expected states for time k. If we just look at what
我们在时间点 k 得到两种预期状态
the distribution on the vehicle's s coordinate looks
如果我们要观察这两种预期状态下车辆的坐标分布
like for the two expected states, this is what we see.
结果是这样的
Where the red curve gives the probability density function of S for turning right,
这里 红色曲线给出了 S 右转的概率密度分布函数
the blue curve represents going straight
蓝色曲线代表直行
and the observation at timestep k is somewhere here.
观察时间步进 k 大约在这里
We can see that this observation is substantially more
我们可以看到 与直行相比
consistent with turn right than it is with go straight.
这个观察值与右转基本相符
This is measured by the likelihood of the observation as
此结果通过对每个模型的观察值进行可能性度量得出
for each model and the probability of
而每种行为的几率
each behavior is a function of these likelihoods
则是这些可能性
and of the probabilities computed in the previous timestep.
以及上一观察时间点计算出的几率的一个函数
The important quantity for the AMM is
对于 AMM 最重要的量是
the ratio of these likelihoods after they get multiplied by the previous probability.
这些可能性与前一可能性相乘后得出的比率值
The equation ends up looking like this,
最终的方程看起来像这样
where this term is the probability of model I
这里 这个项代表时间点 K 的模型 I 的几率
at timestep K. This term is the probability of
而这个项表示在时间点 K-1
model I at timestep K minus one and
的模型 I 的几率
this L term is the likelihood of the observation at time K for that model.
L 表示在时间点 K 上的观察值计算出的可能性
The denominator just serves to normalize our probabilities so that they all sum to one.
这里的分母是为了规格化我们的几率数值 使所有几率之和为1
M, in this situation would be two since we are only considering two maneuvers.
M 项在这里取值为2 因为我们只考虑了2种动作